Finding Aid for the Elizabeth Hastings Peeler Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Elizabeth Hastings Peeler Collection
1919-1994
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0330
.42 linear feet
Biography/History
Elizabeth Hastings Peeler (1914-1993), received a 1936 Bachelor of Arts degree from Vanderbilt University, a 1939 Bachelor of Arts degree in Library Science from Emory University, and in 1950 a Masters of Science degree in Library Science from Columbia University. She was an international affairs librarian for University of Miami and Florida International University, once taught in Africa, and worked for the United Nations. She retired in 1977. In 1985, Florida Governor Bob Graham appointed her to the Long-Term Care Ombudsman Council.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains a handwritten biographical sketch, a typed book review by Elizabeth Peeler, incoming/outgoing correspondence, magazine articles, and newspaper clippings. The vast majority of magazine articles and newspaper clippings relate to the career of Peter Taylor, a Southern writer. The .165 linear foot collection is housed in 25 acid-free file folders.
- Biographical Sketch
  - Handwritten
- Book Review
  - A Woman of Means — by Peter Taylor [reviewed by Elizabeth Peeler, n.d.
- Correspondence - Outgoing
  - Peter Taylor, May 9, 1985
  - Pat — [Christmas card], December 1989
- Correspondence - Incoming
  - Peter Taylor, September 30, 1978
  - The Schroeders - [photographic Christmas card], December 1988
  - The Schroeders - [photographic Christmas card], December 1988
  - Peter Taylor - [postcard], January 28, 1989
  - Pat Schroeder (Congresswoman), February 7, 1989
  - Jim Schroeder — [Schroeder for Congress Committee], June 26, 1990
- Magazine Articles
  - Judge John T. Peeler, The Eastern Star, August 1919.
  - PW Interviews, Publishers Weekly, January 18, 1985 — written by Wendy Smith Peter Taylor
  - Books Page, Time, February 4, 1985 — written by Paul Gray The Old Forest, and Other Stories — by Peter Taylor
  - Southern Spotlight, Publishers Weekly, May 16, 1986 — written by Bob Summer A Bushel of Books for Tennessee’s Homecoming
  - Books Page, Time, September 29, 1986 — written by Paul Gray A Summons to Memphis — by Peter Taylor
  - Books Page, The New Yorker, November 3, 1986 — written by John Updike A Summons to Memphis — by Peter Taylor
  - People, Time, April 20, 1987. A Summons to Memphis — by Peter Taylor [first American to receive Ritz-Hemingway prize]
- Newspaper Clippings
  - 1981
  - 1984
  - 1985
  - 1986
  - 1987
  - 1988
  - 1989
  - 1991
  - 1993
  - 1994